Anna Ianikova

818.579.0282 • avianikova@gmail.com • Austin, TX

SUMMARY

Experienced Frontend Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the tech industry (8+ years of experience working in IT as a product/project manager closely with engineering and design teams). A software engineer with the ability to challenge others and myself to develop solutions to problems and situations with a growth/learning mindset and cultural awareness powered by international experience. Versed in React, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Git, Github, Axios, and Agile methodology, but committed to consistently learning new skills to further my repertoire.

- Frontend Development
- UX/UI Design

- Agile and Scrum Methodologies
- QA Fundamentals

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE, Austin, Texas

01/2022 - Present

Jr. Software Engineer

Created 3 personal projects focused on real-world applications of data science principles and best practices; built skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, GitHub, and SQL. Developed a portfolio of individually and collaboratively focused in-class projects, including:

- Personal website: Portfolio landing page built with React, Javascript, and CSS https://thriving-pithivier-7776c4.netlify.app/
- Weather App: My very first website was created to display objects from an API. This project includes skills in React, and JavaScript with basic HTML & CSS https://wizardly-stonebraker-ac8f03.netlify.app/
- Dictionary App: Second project built with React and open-source API https://wondrous-salamander-e40509.netlify.app/

PRO UNLIMITED, Austin, Texas Software development company Product Manager	08/2016 - 04/2019
EXPORT PORTAL, Los Angeles, USA International B2B e-Commerce Platform Senior Project Coordinator	10/2019 – 12/2022
CITRONIUM, Yoshkar-Ola, Russia Software development company Project Manager	08/2016 - 04/2019
MOSCOW BUSINESS SCHOOL, Moscow, Russia One of the leading business schools in Russia International Project Manager	11/2014 - 08/2016
MONORAY, Yoshkar-Ola, Russia Software development company Product Manager	01/2014 - 10/2014

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Mari State University Graduate Certificate in Linguistics with Honors Bachelor and Master's Degree in Public Relations with Honors	Yoshkar-Ola, Russia 2014 2013
Heinrich Heine University German Language Academic Program, DAAD Scholarship Recipient	Dusseldorf, Germany 2012
University of Virginia Darden School of Business Digital Product Management (Credential ID UMK2M2XADD7P)	2021

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Expertise:

- Project Management: Jira, Confluence, Trello, YouTrack
- Analytics & Visualization: SQL, Tableau, SmartSheet
- Prototyping and Development: Google Drawings, draw.io, Balsamiq, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, Javascript
- Other: CRM and ERP systems, MS Office, G-Suite

Additional languages: German, Russian